Welcome to our intro to stores and A+ content.
After a brand has been enrolled in and approved by Amazon Brand Registry,
sellers with listing privileges for the brand can begin to use
the full set of brand-specific tools that Amazon offers.
Sellers have listing privileges for a registered brand if they're the product or rights owner who
enrolled the brand.
Other sellers verified as internal to the brand, and resellers authorized by the brand will also
have listing privileges.
Two of the first tools these sellers should consider using for a newly registered brand are stores
and A+ content.
Both stores and A+ content can help enhance a brand's footprint in the Amazon store.
They also prepare those with listing privileges to use brand-specific advertising tools.
A brand's store is a dedicated digital space within the greater Amazon store.
Brands use stores to group their product listings, highlight their value, and tell their story.
A+ content includes enhanced images, text placements, and product comparison charts,
which brands add to their product detail pages to inform and inspire purchases.
Let's review the core features of both tools.
Sellers with listing privileges can create a dedicated store for a registered brand any time by
clicking stores,
then manage stores from the main menu in Seller Central.
This will bring you to our stores homepage, where you can click the Create Store button to get started.
You'll be prompted to create a brand store, which you can update as your brand or products evolve.
During this process, you'll provide the brand name and logo, choose a template for product offerings,
and create tiles for videos, recommended products, and featured deals.
Stores require no coding experience and can be a quick and easy way to design an immersive engaging
experience for customers.
Stores can include sub pages below your homepage, which you can use to organize and highlight a
full catalog of product offerings,
help boost discovery for the brand, and make it easier for customers to compare a full range of
products,
and tell the brand's story with various widgets and other features,
giving customers a centralized place to follow the brand.
Note that after you create a store, it generally appears in the Amazon store within seven business
days,
although review may take longer during peak periods.
A+ content can also help you engage customers from the product detail pages they use to make purchases.
Sellers with listing privileges for a registered brand can add and update A+ content anytime by
clicking Advertising,
then A+ Content Manager in the main menu on Seller Central.
This will bring you to the A+ content homepage.
You'll follow prompts for building enhanced product content, additional brand content, or both.
You can use detailed product images, additional text placements, and product comparison charts to
provide more comprehensive descriptions of your products.
You can also create and reuse content that tells the brand's story and builds brand awareness on
each product detail page.
Like stores, A+ content requires no coding experience.
It can be an effective way to answer customer questions, inspire purchases, and drive traffic to
a brand's store.
Note that, as with stores, new A+ content generally appears in the Amazon store within seven business
days,
although review may take longer during peak periods.
Both stores and A+ content can help customers engage with a registered brand and its products.
After you've set them up, you can start using brand-specific advertising tools to help drive customer
traffic to them.
For example, you can use a Sponsored Brands campaign to link customers searching the Amazon store
to the A+ content on product detail pages and to a brand's store.
Or you can use a sponsored display campaign to link interested customers using an app to A+ content.
This combination of advertising and enhanced content can increase the chance that a customer will
purchase a product.
It can also increase the likelihood that they'll return to a brand when thinking about making another
purchase.
This concludes our intro to stores and A+ content.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.